blippar.com 2018-05-05

# Privacy Policy | Blippar

**Blippar Privacy Policy**

**Last modified: 1 st February 2018**

[Pour voir les règles de confidentialité en français, cliquez ici](https://blippar.com/en/privacy/politique-de-confidentialite/) 

Blippar is the world's first visual discovery browser, using augmented reality, artificial intelligence and computer vision technology to transform how you connect with the world.

The Blippar application for mobile devices (“Blippar App” or the “App”) uses the camera on your smartphone, whilst the App is enabled, to recognise images through the camera and show on-screen dynamic content on top of what you see in the real world – what’s known as 'augmented reality'.

We use artificial intelligence, computer vision technology and other functionality – including, where you choose to enable it, facial recognition technology – to make this happen.  Scanning an item or a person with your mobile device is something we call 'blipping', which launches an augmented reality experience we call a 'blipp'. 

You can find out more about our App and how it works at <https://blippar.com/en/resources/faq/>.   

As part of our offering to other businesses, we enable them to offer you blipps and augmented reality content via the Blippar App, their own devices and/or web platforms as part of their advertising and marketing campaigns.

At Blippar we are working to build a service which is useful and fun for our users and in doing that we are absolutely committed to your privacy.  The Blippar App, Services, websites and related APIs and tools covered by this policy are constantly evolving as we add new features to improve your experience, but our users' privacy remains at the heart of what we do. As the Blippar App changes, so might the information we use and how we use it.   We encourage users to consult this policy whilst using Blippar and we will notify you of any material changes to it through the Blippar App.

The technology behind Blippar is complex, and you can do different things using the Blippar App, Services, websites and related APIs and tools, so we have tried to explain the ways we collect and use your data in a straightforward way so you know what is going on.   We may provide sets of FAQs on how Blippar works and for specific products and features to help you understand them better.   We welcome any feedback or questions you may have on privacy matters and how we use your data – please contact us at [privacy@blippar.com](mailto:privacy@blippar.com).

**Who we are**

Blippar is a technology business headquartered in London, UK, with local subsidiary companies in various countries around the world, including the United States. For the purposes of European data protection law, Blippar.com Ltd (registered in England and Wales, number 07446749) is the ultimate data controller for personal data collected, processed and used through the App. 

**What this document tells you**

When you use the Blippar App, websites, APIs, tools and any other services we may make available, you will share some information with us. When we talk about the Blippar "App" or "Service", we mean all the websites, APIs, tools and other products, services and features offered by Blippar.

This policy is designed to explain to you what information about you Blippar collects in providing the Blippar App and Services, how that information is used and shared and how you can control what happens with that information.

**What information we collect**

When you use the Blippar App or use our Services we receive certain information about you, including:

  * digital images of the objects and people you are blipping
  * the blipp and other online content you are shown and link to and your interests and preferences suggested by what you’ve blipped and what online content you’ve viewed
  * a unique user ID, which we assign to you, against which we maintain data about you and your use of the Blippar App
  * your location (both generally in respect of your locale, e.g. the UK and specifically, exact latitude and longitude coordinates)
  * certain mobile network and device identifiers to help us provide our services including the IP address that your internet network provider may allocate to your mobile or other internet enabled device.

We also receive additional personal information about you which you choose to give us. For example, if you want access to our facial recognition features from the Blippar App or a third party app, you may be asked to register some basic information with us so we can provide our Services to you, including your email address, nick name, profile image and confirmation that you are at least 16 years old.

You don’t have to create an augmented reality face profile in order to use the Blippar App and Services but, if you do, we will collect a series of images of your face which we will store against the digital face signature we create as part of the registration process. This includes any unsuccessful images, which we will use for troubleshooting purposes. If you choose to make your profile visible to others then, when someone blipps your face or an image of it, it will search against our database of facial signatures and will also store these scanned images that have been taken of you (see section on facial recognition here for more detail).

We will also collect certain content that you have chosen to associate with your Halo that is specific to you. This may include information from third party sources, such as other social media sites.

When you use our Blippbuilder tool and/or our APIs, content generated or procured by you might be transferred to the Blippar platform (“User Generated Content”).

A history of your recent blipps, will be stored in accordance with our caching practices. Blippar also uses cookies - please see cookies section below for details.

**How we use your information**

We use your personal information to provide, monitor and improve the Blippar App, website, services and the technology which supports them and to provide you with a great, personalised experience.   We will occasionally use your information to contact you, for instance if you send us requests or ask us questions about Blippar or if there are technical or operational issues or updates which we think our users need to know about.  

We may also send you free newsletters and emails that directly promote the Blippar Service. When you receive such promotional communications from us, you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mail you receive. We do need to send you certain communications regarding the Blippar service and you will not be able to opt out of those communications – e.g., communications regarding updates to our [Terms of Use](https://blippar.com/en/terms/) or this Privacy Policy.

We provide augmented reality services to brands so that their marketing materials are blippable, providing users with augmented reality content when they blipp materials such as magazine adverts or product packaging.  Where we do this, we also report to our clients on an aggregated basis (so that no individuals are identified), the location of users blipping their content, how long they spent interacting with the client's blippable content or our app generally and how they use our app.

We also disclose information in the aggregate to third parties for marketing and strategic development purposes.

**This section applies to facial recognition**

We understand that engaging with facial recognition technology may be a new experience for you. At Blippar, we have worked hard to ensure that facial recognition is simple, fun and safe and that it puts the user in control.

**_Use of our facial recognition features is intended for users who are at least 16 years old_**.  If you are aged under 16, please get your parent/guardian's permission before you provide any personal information to Blippar. Users under 16 without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information, including any images of your face.  By registering your facial signature, you are representing to us that you are aged 16 or over or have the specific consent of your parent or guardian to use Blippar, including in respect of facial recognition. 

**_Creating facial signatures_**

You can register your face for recognition through the Blippar App or a third party app by pointing the phone camera at your face; you then have to follow the prompts, guiding your nose to follow the dot around the screen so the camera sees your face from different angles.  That process is called the ‘Blippar cross’. This is important as it helps to creates your unique face signature – a biometric print which is essentially a set of measurements of your face features, which the Blippar app can then use to recognise you – kind of like your fingerprint. The number of angles captured during this process also makes it difficult to create a fake profile using someone else’s face, however, you can report any suspicious profiles by emailing us at [accountsupport@blippar.com](mailto:accountsupport@blippar.com). Once the registration process is complete, you should be recognizable when someone blipps you and you can connect them to your augmented reality profile or other content.

By registering your face for recognition, you understand and agree that Blippar will use your details, including images of your face, in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

If you are accessing our facial recognition features from a third party app, the registration and recognition process will be similar, but the user experience and content shown on recognition (including who can access your information) will be determined by that third party, whose Terms of Use and Privacy Policy may also apply. 

**_Who can see my profile?_**

Creating a facial signature does not mean that people can automatically see your profile. Blippar users can see your augmented reality face profile only if they blipp you in person, or an image of you, and you have consented to your profile being visible. Users cannot blipp images stored on the same phone they blipp with.

By default, your profile will be invisible when you first create your profile and any time you choose to make it invisible after that.  An invisible profile can only be seen by you. If you make your pfoile invisible after another Blippar user has blipped it, they will be alerted to this if they try to bring up your profile again from their recent blipping history.

We do not allow users to search the database of facial signatures and images to find someone specific and we do not, apart from in very limited circumstances, share facial signatures and profile information with any third party – for more details on such circumstances, see Will Blippar share my facial data?

**_What happens if I haven’t registered my face for recognition?_**

If a person being blipped is not a Blippar user, is a Blippar user but does not have a facial signature, or has made their public invisible, the App will not display their augmented reality profile. In this case, a celebrity lookalike may be shown instead based on the public figure our platform thinks they most closely resemble. If another user scans your face while using the Blippar App, and you do not already have a face signature, this will not automatically create one for you.

If you blipp a public figure in real life or an image of them from print or digital media, you will see online content which relates to them and which has been discovered in Blipparsphere. To do this, we have created simple facial signatures for public figures from photographs which are generally available online.

**_How are facial signatures stored?_**

To make our facial recognition Services work, we retain the facial images you take of your face when creating your facial signature, and of public figures from online sources, and the facial signatures we create from them all on secure Amazon Web Services (“AWS”) data centres, stored separately from your account data for additional security.  We need to do this in order for the App to recognise a face as belonging to a user with a facial signature and for the Service to work.

**_For how long does Blippar keep information relating to facial recognition?_**

Blippar will store your facial images, facial signature and content you have added to your profile for as long as your profile exists. This length of time might be determined at the time of registration (eg. for an event), otherwise, we may keep your facial signature and profile active until you request deletion. Details of how to request deletion of your profile and associated data are in the section below. 

**_What control do I have over my facial signature and profile?_**

A facial signature of a user is only created if the user wants to create one.  We do create simple facial signatures from publicly available online images of public figures, and use them to present information relating to them that is available online. 

You can typically delete your facial signature and your associated augmented reality profile, or make it invisible to other users, via the options on the Blippar App. If you can’t see that option, just email us at [privacy@blippar.com](mailto:privacy@blippar.com) and we can do it for you.

Public figures can request to switch off the facial recognition feature by emailing us at [privacy@blippar.com](mailto:privacy@blippar.com) and we will remove the facial recognition piece so their Blipparsphere profile does not come up when they are blipped. The information associated with them will stay in the knowledge graph.

If you have any questions or concerns about facial recognitions or data that we hold about you then please contact us at [privacy@blippar.com](mailto:privacy@blippar.com) _._

**_Will Blippar share my facial data?_**

We will not share your facial signatures or profile information with our clients or third parties, other than when making your profile visible to other users if it is set to visible or where we are required to share such information with service providers who perform services on our behalf. The only exception to this is where there are legal reasons for us to disclose, such as in response to a search warrant or court order. We take keeping this biometric data secure extremely seriously and use AWS, one of the most secure data centres in the world. See sections entitled with third parties and with third parties for legal reasons for further detail.

We will collect aggregated statistics (which are not unique to you and cannot identify you) about how our users or categories of users are interacting with your augmented reality face profile and other services we offer using facial recognition.

**This Section Has General Information About Your Personal Information**

**Where we store your information**

The information we collect in relation to you is stored on data centres operated by our third party providers.  Our AWS data centres are currently based in Europe and the United States. By using Blippar service, you consent to the hosting of your personal information on these servers, which may involve the transfer of your personal data outside of the country it was collected.  It is important to note that countries have different regulations in relation to personal information, including in relation to rights of access by law enforcement authorities.

**Can I find out what personal information Blippar holds about me?**

You have the right to request details of the personal information Blippar holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. In most cases, we will also be able to provide you with a copy of the personal information we hold. We need to establish your identity as we do not want to release information to the wrong person, so we may ask for documents that prove your identity. Please address requests and questions about this to [_privacy@blippar.com_](mailto:privacy@blippar.com)

**How we share your information**

We may share information about you in the following ways:

  * **With other Blippar users**. We may share the following information with other users: 
    * Information about you, such as your nick name as you have provided it, with other users but we will not share your contact details with them
    * Your augmented reality face profile and the content you have posted in it, where you have set your profile to visible mode
    * Information about how you have interacted with the Blippar app, based on the blipping activity of you and those users who blipp your face
  * **With third parties.** We may share your information with the following third parties: 
    * With organisations who provide services or technology to us.  See here in respect of facial data specifically \- Will Blippar share my facial data? We may share information about you with service providers who perform services on our behalf – for instance our data centre providers who host the Blippar technology and data and partners that provide services to us. These third-party providers have access to your data only for the purpose of performing services on our behalf.
    * We provide augmented reality services to brands so that their marketing materials are blippable, showing users augmented reality content when they blipp the materials. Where we do this, we also report to our clients on an aggregated basis where users accessing their blippable content are located, how long they spent interacting with the client's Blippar content or our app generally and how they use the Blippar app.
    * We also disclose information in the aggregate (so that no individuals are identified) to third parties for marketing and strategic development purposes.
  * **With third parties for legal reasons.**  We may share information about you if we believe that disclosing the information is needed to:
    * comply with any valid legal process, governmental request, or applicable law, rule, or regulation
    * investigate, remedy, or enforce potential breaches of our [Terms of Use](https://blippar.com/en/terms/) and/or [Community Guidelines](https://blippar.com/en/app/community/)
    * protect the rights, property, and safety of us, our users, or others
    * detect and resolve any fraud or security concerns
  * **With our affiliates**. We may share your information with entities within the Blippar family of companies
  * **With third parties if Blippar is acquired or its legal structure undergoes a reorganisation or all or a big chunk of our business is transferred to another company or companies.** In that circumstance we may share your information with that company before and after the transaction closes so that we can still provide you with a great service.

**How old do I have to be to use Blippar?**

Blippar’s services are intended for users who are at least 13 years old (other than our facial recognition features, which are for people age 16 years old and above).  Blippar does not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13.

**How long will Blippar keep my personal information?**

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary to provide access to our app and websites and will not hold onto it once we have processed a request by you to delete your account. 

By emailing [delete@blippar.com](mailto:delete@blippar.com), you can have all account data deleted – if you do this a red flag goes on the database and, while Blippar cannot use the personal information, it stays on the system for a period for administration purposes before being deleted automatically. If you only want to delete facial signature and/or your associated augmented reality, we can delete this information whilst keeping your Blippar account intact.

If we are subject to a legally binding requirement to retain user information for a specific period, this may (subject to the law in question) override your ability to require deletion.

Please remember that other Blippar users may have content and information you have made available through Blippar, for instance through screen shots or other image capture and we do not control how they use or how long they keep that content.

**Web browser cookies**

_What is a cookie?_

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your computer, tablet or mobile phone web browser from a website’s computer (i.e., a Web server) and is stored on your computer, table or mobile phone web browser.

_How does Blippar use cookies?_

In general terms, Blippar only uses cookies to record information about your preferences, how you prefer to use our websites and our services. They allow us to tailor our app, websites and our other services to your interests.

Information supplied by cookies can help us to analyse the profile of visitors to our app and website and users of our other services and help us to provide you with a better user experience.

_Third party cookies_

We use analytics cookies and mobile device equivalents served by our third party providers to analyse how users use our app and websites and report back to us. This helps us work out what elements of the app and websites are working and helps us improve them. In the future, we may have digital advertising partners who may use cookies, mobile equivalents and other technologies to collect information to support the delivery of interest-based advertising to users. We will ensure you are properly notified including through updates to this policy before that happens.

_Third Party Cookies in embedded content on Blippar pages_

Please note that during your visits to our websites you may notice some cookies that are not related to Blippar or Blippar’s partners. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Flickr, you may be presented with cookies from these websites (“Third Party Websites”). Blippar does not control the dissemination of these cookies. Any information that you provide on or to a Third Party Website or that is collected by a Third Party Website is provided directly to the owner or operator of the Third Party Website and is subject to the owner’s or operator’s privacy policy. Blippar is not responsible for the content, privacy or security practices and policies of any Third Party Website. To protect your information we recommend that you carefully review the privacy policies of all Third Party Websites that you access. 

_Blippar cookies and how to reject cookies_

If you wish to control what cookies are set on your device through our app, websites or other services then you can by changing the settings on your personal computer or mobile device web browser. It is important to note that if you change your settings and block certain cookies, this means that certain personalised features and other functionality cannot then be provided to you and accordingly you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the app, websites or our other services features.

_Other information collected from web browsers_

Your web browser may also provide Blippar with information about your device, such as an IP address and details about the browser that you are using. It may also provide Blippar with access to details of your personal computer or mobile device’s location.

_Responding to “Do Not Track” signals_

Our websites and App do not have the capability to respond to “Do Not Track” signals received from various web browsers.

_The security of your information_

In addition, we take reasonable administrative, physical and electronic measures designed to protect the information that we collect from or about you (including your personal information) from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. We use encryption methods when storing and transmitting. Please be aware, however, that no method of transmitting information over the Internet or storing information is completely secure. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of any information.

**Mobile devices**

When you download or use the app on your mobile device, information may be accessed from or stored to your mobile device. This is used in a similar way to a web browser cookie, such as by enabling the apps to ‘remember’ you or provide you with the content you have requested.

Your web browser on your device or your mobile device’s operating system may also provide Blippar with information about your mobile device, such as a device identifier or IP address. Device identifiers may be collected automatically, such as the device ID, IP address and apps ID (a unique identifier relating to the particular copy of the Apps you are running). In the future we may use mobile device identifiers for advertising use which perform a similar role to cookies, like the IDFA used by Apple devices and the Advertising ID used by Android devices.

**Changes to Blippar's Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time so please check from time to time. Major changes to the data we collect or how we use and share it will be notified to you through the Blippar app. The date of the most recent revisions will appear at the beginning of this policy. If you do not agree to these changes, please do not continue to use the Blippar app, websites or our other services to submit personal information to Blippar.

**Contacting Blippar about this Privacy Policy**

If you any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy please contact:

The Data Protection Officer  
5th Floor West,  
1 London Bridge  
London  
SE1 9BG

Email: [_privacy@blippar.com_](mailto:privacy@blippar.com)
